Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Chamber Of Commerce records, 1919-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Chamber Of Commerce records 1919-1969
Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce.
85741 Bm 2 UBMm
Organizational records and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
4 linear feet
1 oversize folders
These records came to the library in 1971 and 1973 from the organization (donor no. 1299 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce was established in 1906.
The records of the Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce include correspondence, minutes of meetings of the board of directors, subject files, photographs, and newspaper clippings concerning community projects. There are also papers concerning the work of Economic Development Committee and the Central Business District Committee, and the development of Greater Ann Arbor Research Park.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Boards of trade--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1931-1940.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1941-1950.; Municipal government--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan--Social life and customs--20th century.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Industry.; Rededication Week (1946: Ann Arbor, Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Bendix Corporation.; Concordia College (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Conductron Corporation.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Freedom Train.; Hill Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Industry--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Liberty Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Main Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Parades and processions.; Parke, Davis & Company.; State Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Aerial photographs.; Photographs.
- Chamber of Commerce records
  - Minutes of board of directors meetings
    - April 1924-September 1926 (Box 1)
    - 1930s, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors papers, including lists of members, minutes of meetings, and election ballots 1943-1952 (Box 1)
  - Proposed hotel for Ann Arbor 1926 (Box 1)
  - Trade Dollars 1930s (Box 1)
  - National Housing Act 1930s (Box 1)
  - Mackinaw Bridge Project 1936 (Box 1)
  - City-County Health Department 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - War Bond Drive 1941-1945 (Box 1)
  - Project to have ship named "Ann Arbor" 1943 (Box 1)
  - Committees of the Chamber of Commerce 1942-1952 (Box 1)
  - "Freedom Train" (traveling display of historic American documents) 1948 (Box 1)
  - National Student Association Purchase Card System 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Building Association 1942-1944 (Box 1)
  - Dissolution of the Building Association 1942-1944 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor, historical information (Box 1)
  - History of the Chamber of Commerce (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and financial reports (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    (see also oversize folder UBMm)
    - Ann Arbor Street views 1920s (Box 1)
    - Commercial and other building developments 1960s (Box 1)
      (include aerial views)
    - Houses (Hill Street) (Box 1)
    - Huron River; rural views; views from Boulevard (Box 1)
    - Rededication Week 1948 (Box 1)
      (Freedom Train)
  - Scrapbook January-February 1927 concerning the activities of the Chamber of Commerce (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook 1939-1940 concerning the annual Ann Arbor Flower Show (Box 2)
  - Financial records January 1930-September 1943 (Box 2)
  - Ledger book containing stock certificates of the Ann Arbor Building Association (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea (Box 2)
  - Economic Development Committee 1957-1967 (Box 3)
  - Greater Ann Arbor Research Park (Box 3)
  - Greater Ann Arbor Research Park (Box 4)
  - Contacts with Electronics Industries (Box 4)
  - Central Business District Committee (Box 4)